OPHIR BFTSFR

Highly motivated Product Analyst with a great passion for creating knowledge from data, in order to make the best decisions. Experienced in Statistical Analysis and Econometrics. skilled in SQL, Python, R, Excel, Visualization tools, and have great self-learning ability.

PROFESSIONAL HISTORY

2022-01 2023-01

Google, Waze

Product Analytics

- Tel-Aviv. Israel
- Team-member of the Trips-DS team in Waze-Data-Guild and in Waze-Carpool-Squad
- · Big-Data research and analysis on top of Google Cloud Platform (GCP).
- · Working closely with product managers and developers on feature development, Experiments, user classification and monitoring key metrics.
- · Productization tables for the data warehouse.
- · Building dashboards and conducting in-depth research.
- A/B testing of new features

2021-01 2021-12

Ministry of Finance

Research Analyst

Jerusalem, Israel

- · Student in the Research-Team of 'Wage and Labor Agreements' Division.
- End-to-end analysis of the salaries and working conditions for +700K of Israel public sector workers.
- Extensive experience in R programming. Building automated analyses.
- · Writing research reports and creating complex visualizations.
- Publication of reports that have received public interest. (example).

2020-01 2020-12

Department of Economics

Research Assistant

Tel-Aviv, Israel

- Economometric research of crime data across the United States.
- · Analysis of geographic data using Python.

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

2018 2021

B.A. in Economics

Tel Aviv University

Tel-Aviv, Israel

- · Graduated Cum Laude.
- Extended mathematics studies.
- · Excellence in Microeconomics and Econometrics studies.

2018 1

B.S. in Computer Science

The Open University

Tel-Aviv, Israel

2021

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

2021 today

Tel Aviv University

Teaching Assistant

- Tel-Aviv, Israel
- 2021: Economics in the Big Data World, Undergraduate Program.
- 2022: Economics in the Big Data World, Undergraduate Program. All course videos are in Youtube.
- 2022: Doing magic with Data, Kellogg-Recanati MBA Program.

2021 today

Reichman University

Teaching Assistant

- Herzliah, Israel
- 2022: Data Science for Business, Mannheim & Reichman MBA Program.
- 2022: Data Analysis for Business Applications, AMBA Program.
- · 2022: Exploratory Data Analysis, GMBA Program. All course videos are in Youtube.



REACH ME AT

- **J** +972 53-420-9480
- ophir.betser@gmail.com
- github.com/ophirbetser
- in linkedin.com/ophirbetser

TECHNICAL SKILLS

SQL

R

Data Visualization

Python

ait

Airflow

Excel

Econometrics

Machine Learning

Web Scraping

HTML

CSS

SOFT SKILLS

Research

Teamwork

Problem-solving

Teaching

Presentation

Self-Learning Ability

Attention to details